<u>i.carrie.sampson@gmail.com</u>

646-346-3232

www.linkedin.com/in/carriesampson https://github.com/carriesampson www.carriesampson.com

A strategic digital problem-solver & web developer, combining creative UI with technical, and project development expertise into a rich mixture of energy and passion for existing and emerging technologies. I love helping to materialize personal, and team ambition into action, creating smart and flexible solutions.

PRIOR ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- 10+ years digital project management leadership and production experience on major Consumer and Pharmaceutical Brands across web/mobile, app, display/native media, digital publishing & content management systems
- 3+ years front-end HTML/CSS development in various roles as needed in support of development teams (self-taught)
- International infrastructure and PMO/VMO process development/execution and roll-out in multiple agency roles with cross-office implementation/optimization of efforts across US, UK, Costa Rica, India, Denmark, Singapore, Finland
- Establishment of media capabilities for previously non-media agencies, creating new revenue work streams, and establishing core teams for creation, deployment, measurement and optimization of native, display and social media approaches

TECHNICAL SKILLS

<u>Core Skills</u>: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, EJS, NodeJS, AngularJS, Angular Material, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Postgres, SQL, Mongoose, Express, Mongo DB, JSON, AJAX, SASS, JChart, Express API, Rails API, various API integrations, Postman, Heroku <u>CMS</u>: Joomla, Drupal, Custom CMS | <u>Media</u>: Nativo, Sharethrough, Brightcove, Flite, Celtra | <u>Workflow</u>:: Atlassian/JIRA, WorkFront, ProofHQ, Trello | <u>Analytics</u>: Google Analytics, CoreMetrics | <u>Other</u>: Geth, Go-Ethereum

CURRENT EXPERIENCE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY
Web Development Fellow

New York, NY & Remote [Sep 2017 – Feb 2018]

- Participated in a full-time (immersive) Full Stack Web Development program, completing in-class and personal projects using team, pair and individual programming methodology.
- Created data-driven, real-world solutions focused on software and application development using industry standard web
 development principles and best practices.
- Project portfolio includes the following work with associated details for use of technologies:
 - Nim Dragons (Game) https://carriesampson.github.io/Nim-Dragons/
 - o Bartenda (Web App) https://bartenda.herokuapp.com/bartenda
 - Bestivals (MEAN Web App with Express API) https://bestivalsapp.herokuapp.com/
 - o ToolieBox (Web App with Rails API) https://tooliebox.herokuapp.com/
 - Xchem (Web App with Rails API) https://xchem.herokuapp.com/

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MCCANN TORRE LAZUR Senior Project Manager Parsippany, NJ [Oct 2016 – Sep 2017]

- Pod and team leadership with direct management of brand launches and label updates across Eisai and Daiichi-Sankyo, with oversight responsibilities for Novartis and Actelion and Allergan Brands.
- Envision and plan complex project and technical strategies for execution of successful launches.
- Crafted, presented and sold agency-wide process updates with following agency rollout creating measureable increase in team efficiencies, reduction of rounds and associated errors and maximization of resources.
- Developed and rolled out previously non-existing project estimating methodology with successful transition of ownership from Account Services into PMO with later roll out of added financial reporting templates within the PMO team.
- Created and implemented department-wide timeline and scheduling standards for increased PMO efficiency.

TIME INC., CONTENT SOLUTIONS DIVISION Digital Project Management Director

New York, NY [Mar 2013 – Nov 2015]

• Senior leadership [PMO/VMO] and highest point of escalation for Project and Product Management, UX, Solutions Architecture, Prototyping, Development & QA teams for the following Client base: Comcast, Ford, Charles Schwab, LandRover, Allstate, BOA, Golds Gym, Dewar's, Chase and Macy's among others.

- Accountable for digital estimates/budgets/SOW for digital work including forecasting and reconciliation.
- Pioneer of Time Inc. capabilities for native product development, creating inter-divisional procedures and completing the 1st native media launches with ongoing direction of native and display media efforts.
- Accountable for digital process inception/development, improvement and continued optimization
- Hands on project and/or product management of technically complex and large scale initiatives/solutions.

VERTIC, INC. Executive Director, Project Management

New York, NY [Apr 2012 – Mar 2013]

- Senior leadership [PMO/VMO] and highest point of escalation for all project and product work across the following Client base: AARP, Microsoft, Siemens, PTC, SAP, Phillips, Nickelodeon, Viacom.
- Interim General Manager responsible for Project Management, Technology, UX and Design teams.
- Accountable for infrastructure and digital process inception/development with subsequent implementation and continued optimization across New York, Copenhagen and Singapore offices.
- Responsible for international (NY, Denmark, Singapore) resource planning, management and conflict resolution.
- Direct responsibility for creation/growth of display and social media planning/ buying capabilities with responsibility for media strategy, research & recommendations.

DIGITAS HEALTH
Associate Director, Project Management

New York, NY [Feb 2011 – Apr 2012]

- PMO/VMO accountability for the following Pharma Client base: BMS/Eliquis Brand (Global & US), Boehringer-Ingelheim/ Spiriva Brand, Pfizer/Toviaz & Detrol Brands, Sanofi-Aventis/Auvi-Q New Product/Brand Launch.
- Executed site redesign/launch of Spiriva.com with corresponding Patient Adherence Program and inclusion of 15 companion digital re-launch tactics such as CRM Program, Animated Adherence Videos, Illustrations and Media.
- Responsible for resource planning across my book of business to cover both Project Management needs and high level staffing/planning of resources across all interdepartmental capabilities.
- Financial accountability (reconciliation/forecasting/burns) across my book of business, both on a project-by-project basis and for communication to high finance.

AKQA INC.

Senior Project Manager

New York, NY

[Jul 2009 – Feb 2011]

- PMO/VMO accountability for the following Client base: Smirnoff (Global & US), Johnson & Johnson, Kraft (Wheat Thins and Miracle Whip Brands), Motorola, Ann Taylor, Ann Taylor LOFT, Benjamin Moore Paints, Deloitte, Thompson Reuters.
- Co-direction for Project Management team, accountable for team building and process development
- Executed site redesign/launch of Ann Taylor, Ann Taylor LOFT and Smirnoff Global website with localization of 60 markets with localized content management capabilities in over 20 languages and local dialects.
- Accountable for budget planning, tracking, analysis, actualizing and burn/reconciliation reporting across my book of business.

BBDO WORLDWIDE

New York, NY
Senior Web Producer

[Oct 2007 – Jul 2009]

- Leadership of pre-production work in website and digital media development, through the Strategy, UX and Design phases of the project lifecycle with continued management of technical/animation/video development and QA through to launches in my Client base: Starwood Luxury Hotels & Suites, Target Corporation, AT&T Wireless.
- Financial accountability (reconciliation/forecasting/burns) across my book of business,
- Responsible for multiple vendor and freelance resource relationships and cost structures.

DIGITAS, INC. (formerly Modem Media) Freelance - Manager, Digital Delivery Management (Project-based)

East Norwalk, CT [May 2007 – Oct 2007]

- Management of digital projects throughout the project lifecycle across multiple teams and deliverables for deliverables including website, digital media, sweepstakes development, email marketing, forum/blog creation and video production to achieve all necessary launches for Delta Airlines/Skymiles "Delta Siteseer Challenge" Contest.
- Responsibilities include: resource allocation, estimating/budgeting, project planning/scheduling, risk mitigation and advisement, quality control, management of client engagement (presentation specifics), overall balance of quality/cost/schedule, and post project analysis.

EDUCATION

SUNY College at Cortland, Cortland, NY BA, Communications Studies Cortland, NY Concentrations: Advertising, Mass Media